Miri...
Ah...
Beloved One, what did you come here in search of?
The village is a closed cradle.
If one becomes its captive, one's value shall transition.
Once longings fulfilled, and in eternal peace, their journey will end.
I'm lost. What are these things? I can't rely on the Amagiri since none grow here. And the depth
gauge is beyond its range. On top of that, I'm being chased by that tall thing. Crap. I gotta
stay focused. Get my bearings. If I can at least get back to where I was before...
It's that massive beast! A turbanid dragon! If I recall correctly, they're quite tenacious.
But this one? Just how far is it gonna pursue me?
Damn! I can totally read my movements!
My arm got chipped!
I feel rocks and... What's this?
Can't believe it just puked that stuff up! Could've used a heads up on that one, Liza!
Did it give up? Am I beyond its territory? Damn it! There's gotta be something I can grab!
Hey! Were you following me? My apologies. But I have to get back to my companions. I am grateful that you saved me, though.
Incorrect direction. The place falls to ruin when you are near. I've removed you.
You... did what?
It would be wise to leave as soon as possible. I cannot impede Fapta. Nor can I stop the village.
Or can I stop the village?
What do you mean? If you know something, then explain things to me clearly!
The village is in the other direction. You are going the wrong way.
Uh... okay.
The creatures around here have been unusually active for a while now.
There are no beast deterrents here.
Deterrents?
Objects Fapta gave your companions. Charms made by mixing body hair from Fapta.
And the one to be protected within a Beast of Omen.
Wait a second. You can't mean... those things Mania found.
That's what those are called?
Hey! Then... was that note also from you too?
Fapta began to doubt you were yourself. She decided to test you.
Upon reaching the Shoto Lair, you made no attempt to search for her.
Shoto?
It is imperative you restore your missing data.
Okay. If you know, just tell me. What kind of being am I exactly?
I do not know. I have no data on interference units of your kind.
What was that? Never heard of those.
I am an interference unit. We observe and touch to gather knowledge.
Interference units were placed in each layer, but transmissions from the others have ceased for quite some time.
They may have malfunctioned or been taken.
Your design is similar to mine, but interference units do not typically cross layers.
I question if we share the same creator.
Do you know who this creator is then?
I have not been granted that information.
You, who can go anywhere, please uncover said data.
It has come into view.
The village.
Iru-bu.
Iru.
Hum.
them sooner. The three sages are the important figures who created this village.
Oh goodness, sorry I haven't introduced myself. I'm Riko. I'm a White Whistle. Well, my White
Whistle's in someone else's care right now, but I'm a cave raider.
Adi, that's great.
See you later, Mandapu.
Oh, doing well? That's great. Follow Sue.
Weird, my hand kind of smells like the sun now.
Oh, you're still here.
Excuse me, I wanna ask a favor of you.
Oh?
Can you teach me your language?
In our language, there are lots of words in which many actions and names are stuck together.
Take this one, for example.
Jackopufu.
It means 40% to request, 30% special, and also 30% stimulus.
Oh.
And then this one is Zidubudu.
Oh, that refers to this village, right?
So you already knew. Well done. It's 50% village, 40% cradle, and 10% mother.
So village, cradle, and mother.
Also, look here. This one is understood.
Konbosu.
Thank you, Yenme. Sorry, Rizuchi. Famo. See you later. Rahosu. I want you to do this for me. Or please.
So if you can remember all that, the rest is practice.
Thank you very much.
Don't mention it. I had a lot of fun talking to you today. Hope you find the friends you're looking for.
Yeah!
Interesting. Now I'm going to have to figure a way to get my hands on a human child.
Oh, that's right. By any chance would you happen to have an idea where they might have gone?
Hmm. Well, let me think a bit.
At the edge of this village, there's a place no one dares enter.
Beyond the sacrifice hole, there's a place called Dogupu within the eye.
Now, if we villagers go there, we get, um, we instinctively feel beaten down.
We're unable to go all the way inside.
But since your friends aren't from the village, it wouldn't be strange if they went in there to investigate.
After all, rumor has it the secret of the village lies within Dogupu.
Exciting, isn't it?
I can't see the fuzzy stuff even when I sniff mania.
Same as the village. Seems like there's no force field here.
What's this dark sticky stuff?
Let's keep ourselves close to the wall for now.
What is it, Ma? What's the matter?
The things from the balancing, they're all over the ground.
They're moving, but they're not doing anything to us.
It's okay. Let's stay calm and keep going.
It's filled with tunnels. Which one?
Let's just go ahead and start with this one.
What was that?
Kasimai-maa-maa-maa.
Huh?
You're not...
hollow?
Adi, so I... I still look like a human.
Huh? Wait, what?
Ah, s-sorry, sorry. It's been so long since I've talked to anyone.
If I see something that's kind of strange, I am sorry.
Whoa, you're a human! And you're on the sixth layer!
Are you a... a white whistle?
What? A white... what?
Sorry, I...
My name's Vredo Eriko.
It's a bit long, so people just call me... Vredo Eriko.
And I've been down here a long time.
I spend my days naming these little guys and singing to them.
We have lots of free time. Isn't that right, Kati?
So the sixth layer in white whistle... I don't know what that means, sorry.
And you? Who are you? Why did you come down here to this awful place?
My name's Riko! And I'm looking for Reg and Nanachi!
For who?
Uh... um...
Um...
How about...
Uh, raho-ju-sosu, jin-jitsu, fluffu...
No, what I mean is...
Um, well, would you consider those two your friends?
Yeah, I can't find them anywhere.
So I wondered if they were here.
Ah, do you think that's what that was just now, Jishi?
I got a signal, so I might know about one, their location...
Whoa, are you serious?
Yes, I'd guide you there, but...
Look, I can't take these off myself, you see.
If you touch them while visualizing them releasing, it should work.
Do those mean you're a bad person?
Or something?
Ugh...
Mm-hmm...
This village, its origins aren't very nice.
You could even say it's cursed.
And I, myself, have something to do with that.
In hell, everything gets so dulled.
And in the end, we somehow became the creators of hell.
There was nothing I could do about the establishment of this village.
It was the one thing I opposed.
And as a result, I got sealed away in this darkness.
But, you know, through the signals carried to me, I've watched over the village this whole time.
Though its origin is horrific.
With time, it's evolved, and it's not such a bad place now.
The children who ended up distorted at this gathering place of curses may have lost their human bodies.
But their souls remain, and they manage to keep carrying on.
What was I talking about again?
Oh, yes. Oh, no, I'm not a very good person.
I was blinded by greed and wanted to become something beyond human.
And for that, I cannot be forgiven.
I'm sorry.
The truth is, I don't care if you're a bad person.
Could you take me to my friends?
Once it becomes too late, then that'll be it.
Riko, I can tell you're a good kid, aren't you?
Are you feeling okay?
Sorry about this. It's all because I asked you to come along with me.
You chose that, child. I see you care for each other.
Amazing.
Being here in this space should be an unrelenting agony for children of the village.
Sometimes longing gets the better of instinct.
Right, Riko?
We should go.
It's time for us to start looking for your friends.
Climb up there?
No way!
Impossible!
I can't do it.
My legs have grown so weak.
Thanks, guys.
Amazing.
It looks so different now.
With just the signals I've been receiving, I had no idea.
Could I borrow some clothes?
It'd be bad if I was recognized.
Thanks, Riko. It fits me perfectly.
I've noticed this place has been pretty lively for a while now.
Wonder what's going on.
Uh, yeah.
Oh, uh, could it be time for the luring?
The luring?
I've never seen it in person before.
Maybe I'll stay and watch it this time.
Okay, here we are.
This is it.
The home of Balaf of the Three Sages.
If I'm correct, one of your friends should be here.
But so...
Sorry.
I can't go in there myself.
If they find out I escaped...
Hari...
No, you should go without me.
You wait here.
I'll be just fine.
I have Ma.
Best of luck.
Hello?
Anybody home?
I'm coming in, okay?
Ma.
Uh, pardon me.
I have some business.
Fell off.
Ma.
Hey, are you okay?
Get off, please!
Nanachi!
Wait, human child.
Huh?
Ma.
ma.
Banu. Banu famo. Honde. A human child. Beautiful.
Buroso. Hilo. I am Belaf. What are you in search of?
Uh, yes! Sorry, I came in here looking for Nanachi. And then I found them lying over here. Right, Nanachi?
The fluffy one has already been purchased.
Your friend, to buy Miti from me, gave their entire being.
I cannot uphold Miti anymore, but fluffy Nanachi is here forever now.
Both are here forever, uncontent.
Priyazoji. Kaja did not know how precious Miti is, and told Nanachi about this place.
Nanachi's eyes looked as though they have seen Haku.
Miti, who does not disappear no matter how much is taken, Belaf's favorite.
To Belaf, Miti is something to always eat.
But, Nanachi, please don't hurt Miti anymore. Stop touching her.
So now, Nanachi sold Nanachi to buy Miti.
Haagun. Nanachi has been put to sleep with smoke.
I don't believe it.
Those eyes. You stayed with me back when it was heard.
I remember you. Thank you for being there. It meant a lot.
Human child. You know Miti?
Yes. She's dear to Nanachi. And she saved my life once.
So, um, what must I do to get my friends Nanachi and Miti back?
Miti. The masked man brought with him.
Man called himself Sovereign of Dawn.
On one of his many visits, Miti was with him.
I could tell by scent.
A true immortal.
With the signal of love.
As an intermediary, a strongly crystallized curse.
In some sense, an incarnation of the Netherworld.
I wanted her at any cost.
But, no matter what I offered,
he would not give her to me.
I gave compensation and had her bone in Iru Buru.
All of my 724 limbs.
50% of my body length.
A portion of my sensory organs.
They were permanently reduced and used as payment.
A perfect reproduction of Miti was created.
Even the soul was replicated.
To obtain that, Nanachi offered me absolutely everything.
So, human child, what do you offer me?
I don't know what I can give you since I don't really have anything of value.
So, I need you to tell me.
If you give your entire body, then immediately.
Huh?
A negotiation.
Come on, think!
I'm sure you know.
A whole healthy human child has unimaginable value in this place.
You're being too greedy in what you ask.
My hair, which I've grown out a lot.
And the nails from my left hand.
All the equipment I have on me now.
How does that sound?
It is true.
I was too greedy.
Yeah?
Although, that is not enough.
I will need you to choose one of the following.
Both eyes.
Or both legs.
Or half your organs.
I will not go lower than that.
I want it, but I shall not be greedy.
I will do all that I can so you do not die.
Human child.
It is your choice.
Human luder.
Human luster.
Thank you.